A Finding Aid to the Leo Castelli Gallery Records, circa 1880-2000, bulk 1957-1999, in the Archives of American Art AAA.leocast
Archives of American Art
Leo Castelli Gallery records
bulk 1957-1999
circa 1880-2000
AAA.leocast
Archives of American Art
217.7 Linear feet
The Leo Castelli Gallery records measure 217.7 linear feet and date from circa 1880-2000, with the bulk of the materials dating from the gallery's founding in 1957 through Leo Castelli's death in 1999. The major influence of dealer Leo Castelli and his gallery on the development of mid-to-late twentieth century modern art in America is well-documented through business and scattered personal correspondence, administrative files, exhibition files, extensive artists' files and printed materials, posters, awards and recognitions, photographs, and audio and video recordings. Also included are records for the subsidiary firms of Castelli Graphics and Castelli/Sonnabend Tapes and Films.
Leo Castelli Gallery
Provenance
The Leo Castelli Gallery records were donated to the Archives of American Art by Leo Castelli's wife, Barbara Bertozzi Castelli, and his children, Nina Castelli Sundell and Jean-Christophe Castelli in 2007.
Related Material
Available in the Archives of America Art are three oral history interviews with Leo Castelli. Paul Cummings interviewed Castelli between May 14, 1969 and June 8, 1973; Barbara Rose in July, 1969; and Andrew Decker on May 22, 1997.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original records requires an appointment.
Historical Note
Leo Castelli (1907-1999) was one of America's most noted contemporary art dealers and opened the Leo Castelli Gallery in New York City in 1957. The gallery showcased cutting edge American contemporary art, including Surrealism, Abstract Expressionism, Neo-Dada, Pop Art, Op Art, Color Field painting, Hard-edge painting, Lyrical Abstraction, Minimal Art, Conceptual Art, and Neo-expressionism, among other movements.
Leo Castelli was born as Leo Krauss on September 4, 1907 in Trieste, of Italian and Austro-Hungarian Jewish origin. He married art dealer Ileana Sonnabend in 1932 and the couple lived in Paris up until World War II. They had a daughter, Nina Castelli Sundell. In Paris, Castelli opened his first gallery in 1939. At that time, he was interested in the European Surrealists.
For years after Castelli moved to New York, he worked in his father-in-law's garment business. However, he organized his first American exhibition in 1951, the famous Ninth Street Show of 1951, a seminal event of Abstract Expressionism.
In 1957, he opened the Leo Castelli Gallery in his townhome on E. 77th Street between Madison and Fifth Avenues in New York City. Castelli initially featured European Surrealism, but also curated exhibitions of American Abstract painters, including Jackson Pollock, Willem de Kooning, Cy Twombly, Friedel Dzubas, and Norman Bluhm.
In 1958, Castelli discovered Pop artists Robert Rauschenberg and Jasper Johns and forged a life-long nurturing relationship with both artists. The gallery then began focusing more on Pop Art, Minimalism and Conceptual Art. Beginning in the early 1960s, Castelli's stable included Richard Artschwager, Lee Bontecou, Chryssa, John Chamberlain, Ronald Davis, Dan Flavin, Donald Judd, Ellsworth Kelly, Joseph Kosuth, Roy Lichtenstein, Robert Morris, Bruce Nauman, Larry Poons, James Rosenquist, Ed Ruscha, Salvatore Scarpitta, Richard Serra, Frank Stella, Andy Warhol, and Lawrence Weiner.
Leo and Ileana divorced in 1959, and Ileana returned to Europe. She later moved back to New York and opened a gallery close to Castelli's. The two remained close and together they established the joint venture of Castelli-Sonnabend Films and Tapes to accommodate artists interested in new media.
In the 1970s Leo Castelli opened a downtown SoHo branch of the Leo Castelli Gallery at 420 West Broadway. In the 1980s he opened a second larger downtown exhibition space on Greene Street also in SoHo.
Leo Castelli's second wife was Antoinette Castelli, with whom he also opened Castelli Graphics, an art gallery devoted to prints and photographs, mostly those by Castelli artists. The couple also had a son together, Jean-Christophe Castelli. In 1995 Leo Castelli married Italian art historian Barbara Bertozzi Castelli. She directs the Leo Castelli Gallery today, showing many of the same artists of the gallery's past.
Leo Castelli's unparalleled eye for quality, combined with his extraordinary skill for nurturing and promoting new art and artists, secured his position as one of the most respected and influential advocates of contemporary art for nearly five decades.
Scope and Content Note
The Leo Castelli Gallery records measure 217.7 linear feet and date from circa 1880-2000, with the bulk of the materials dating from the gallery's founding in 1957 through Leo Castelli's death in 1999. The major influence of dealer Leo Castelli and his gallery on the development of mid-to-late twentieth century modern art in America is well-documented through business and scattered personal correspondence, administrative files, exhibition files, extensive artists' files and printed materials, posters, awards and recognitions, photographs, and audio and video recordings. Also included are records for the subsidiary firms of Castelli Graphics and Castelli/Sonnabend Tapes and Films.
The records document the gallery's daily business operations, exhibitions, spaces/buildings, collaborations and joint ventures with other galleries and museums, and its relationship with many artists, dealers, and clients. Artists particularly well-represented throughout the collection include Hanne Darboven, Dan Flavin, Jasper Johns, Donald Judd, Roy Lichtenstein, Robert Morris, Bruce Nauman, Claes Oldenburg, Robert Rauschenberg, James Rosenquist, Richard Serra, Frank Stella, Andy Warhol, and Lawrence Weiner.
Records pre-dating the gallery's establishment in 1957 are primarily newspaper and magazine clippings related to artists, personal photographs and photographs of works of art, and scattered personal business records of Leo Castelli.
General Correspondence is extensive at circa 25 linear feet and consists primarily of the gallery's and Leo Castelli's named and subject correspondence files concerning the gallery's daily operations, exhibitions, artwork installation and fabrication, appraisals, inquiries, loans, sales, consignments, personal and business relationships with artists, and other topics. The general correspondence is arranged either by name of correspondent or topic, and is with museums and galleries, collectors, business associates, artists, employees, and friends. Notes, scattered photographs and slides, and printed materials are often found as enclosures. Leo Castelli's personal correspondence is also found here and consists primarily of solicitations, requests for advice, notes of thanks, congratulations, and invitations.
Letters written by artists in the gallery's stable are somewhat limited. There are scattered letters from artists Christo, Chryssa, Nassos Daphnis, Hanne Darboven, Marisol, Dan Flavin, Jasper Johns, Frederick Kiesler, Robert Morris, Hans Namuth, Bruce Nauman, Nam June Paik, Ray Parker, James Rosenquist, Edward Ruscha, Salvatore Scarpitta, Frank Stella, Cy Twombly, and Jack Tworkov. There are also letters about artists in this series filed under the artists' name.
Collectors and dealers represented within the correspondence include the De Menil family, Mrs. Henry Epstein, Ben Heller, Giuseppe Panza, Alan Power, John and Kimiko Powers, Robert and Carolyn Rowan, Robert and Ethel Scull, and Burton and Emily Tremaine. Museums and galleries for which there is considerable correspondence includes the Dwan Gallery, Ferus Gallery, the Jewish Museum, Museum of Modern Art, Sidney Janis Gallery, Stedelijk Museum, Whitney Museum of American Art, and the Ileana Sonnabend Galerie.
The materials arranged in General Correspondence were originally marked by the gallery as "correspondence" files upon accessioning, and, are thus arranged into their own series. However, in some cases, there appears to be little difference between the General Correspondence and the Administrative Files. Thus, researchers are encouraged to reference both series.
Administrative Files document a wide variety of the gallery's activities and business. Essentially, these are files that were arranged by the gallery according to subject or topic and cover almost all activities except specific exhibitions. These files include records and correspondence about buildings and space, advertising, appraisals, auctions, consignments, loans, miscellaneous business correspondence, index cards, business arrangements with artists, information about artists, interviews with artists (transcripts), history of the gallery, mailings, photograph requests, shipping, and other topics. There are staff notebooks and files and Leo Castelli's notebooks and notes from the late 1950s through the early 1990s. Extensive outgoing chronological correspondence filed in this series dates from 1964-1977. Also found are transcripts of interviews with Leo Castelli, biographical material, and scattered photographs.
Researchers should note that the Administrative Files often overlap and complement the General Correspondence. However, they focus slightly more distinctly on gallery business activities and are arranged mostly by subject or topic, except for the chronological business correspondence. Researchers are encouraged to reference both series. For example, correspondence with and about Jasper Johns may be found in both series, but the administrative files most likely focus on a specific loan, consignment, or business activity or transaction.
Exhibition files provide a thorough history of the gallery's exhibitions, as well as the fabrication and installation of artwork for exhibitions. These files include correspondence, exhibition catalogs, guest books, lists of exhibitions by artist and by year, press releases, sketches and notes, and scattered financial records. Photographs document over 650 exhibitions at Leo Castelli Gallery,including The Ninth Street Show organized by Castelli in 1951, and over 200 exhibitions at other galleries.
Extensive artists' files comprise approximately 40% of the records and are a rich resource of printed and compiled information about the careers of over 120 artists and their relationship with Leo Castelli and the gallery. There are exhibition announcements and catalogs, flyers, invitations, magazine articles and clippings, newspaper clippings, posters, press releases, photographs, and a handful of books. Nearly half of the series is comprised of black and white photographs of artwork, presumably handled by the Leo Castelli Gallery.
Additional printed materials include exhibition announcements, flyers, invitations, magazine articles and clippings, newspaper clippings, press releases, and exhibition posters. Exhibition catalogs are filed with the exhibitions files. The general archives files provide a chronological history of the gallery and its exhibitions. There are also files concerning Leo Castelli and numerous art-related topics. Exhibition posters are found here as well.
Artwork is limited and includes a few works of art and signed posters. Artists represented here include photographer Gianfranco Gorgoni, Robert Morris, Bruce Nauman, Richard Serra and Andy Warhol, as well as others.
The records of the subsidiary Castelli Graphics New York consist of correspondence and administrative files relating to general operations and the sale and loan of prints. Also found are exhibition files, sales records, and scattered financial records. The series provides a wealth of information about Castelli Graphics collaborations with Multiples Inc. in the 1970s.
Also found in the collection are records of Castelli/Sonnabend Tapes and Films, a joint business venture between Leo Castelli Gallery and Sonnabend Gallery from 1974-1985. Records include correspondence, administrative files, exhibition files, artists' files, printed materials, sales and rental records, photographs, and financial records.
The importance and stature of Leo Castelli and the Leo Castelli Gallery to the arts community in New York City and beyond is documented by numerous awards and recognitions, such as framed and unframed certificates, plaques, statues, medals, and scattered photographs.
Nearly seven linear feet of photographs include professional black and white original prints, scattered color photographs, color transparencies, slides and negatives, and disassembled photo albums. The photographs primarily depict social and art events and functions; family and friends of Leo Castelli; and portraits of Leo Castelli and artists and of Leo Castelli with artists, including Richard Artschwager, Jasper Johns, Roy Lichtenstein, Bruce Nauman, Robert Rauschenberg, James Rosenquist, Salvatore Scarpitta, Richard Serra, Frank Stella, and Andy Warhol. Photographs of exhibitions and exhibition installations are filed with the exhibition files.
Audio and video recordings include recordings done by artists, interviews with artists and Leo Castelli, recordings from and of exhibitions, and television programs recorded primarily on cassette tapes, albums, VHS tapes, and ¾" U-Matic tapes. Artists represented include Robert Barry, Barbara Bloom, Hanne Darboven, Dan Flavin, Jasper Johns, Jeff Koons, Roy Lichtenstein, Bruce Nauman, Claes Oldenburg, Robert Rauschenberg, James Rosenquist, Doug and Mike Starn, and Lawrence Weiner, among others.
See Index for list of Exhibitions at the Leo Castelli Gallery and Castelli Graphics
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 11 series:
Series 1: Correspondence, 1948-1999, bulk 1957-1997 (Boxes 1-23, 191, OVs 233-236; 24.6 linear feet)
Series 2: Administrative Files, 1941-1999, bulk 1970s-1990s (Boxes 24-39, 192-193, OVs 237-238; 16.8 linear feet)
Series 3: Exhibition Files, 1951-1999, bulk 1957-1998 (Boxes 40-56, 192, 194-196, OVs 239-241, 280; 21.4 linear feet)
Series 4: Artists Files, 1913-1999, bulk 1960s-1990s (Boxes 57-133, 197-208, OVs 242-243; 89.5 linear feet)
Series 5: Printed Materials, 1949-1998 (Boxes 134-153, 209-211, OVs 244-274, 276, 300; circa 18.6 linear feet)
Series 6: Artwork, circa 1960s-1990s (Boxes 153, 212-213, OVs 275, 277-278; 1.8 linear feet)
Series 7: Castelli Graphics, circa 1950-1999, bulk mid 1970s-early 1990s (Boxes 154-169; 16 linear feet)
Series 8: Castelli/Sonnabend Tapes + Films, 1969-1998 (Boxes 170-174, 214, OVs 279-281; 5.8 linear feet)
Series 9: Awards and Recognition, 1962-1998 (Boxes 175-176, 215-228, OVs 282; 6.3 linear feet)
Series 10: Photographs, circa 1880-1997, bulk 1960s-1990s (Boxes 177-180, 229-231, OVs 283-299; 6.6 linear feet)
Series 11: Sound and Video Recordings, circa 1950s-2000 (Boxes 181-190, 232; 10.3 linear feet)
List of Exhibitions
Below is a chronological listing of over 850 exhibitions and events held at the Leo Castelli Gallery from 1957 to 1999; included are exhibitions at 4 E 77 St (1957-1989), 65 Thompson (1989-1994), 108th St Warehouse (1968-1970), 142 Greene St (1980-1988), 420 W Broadway (1971-1999), and 578 Broadway (1988-1997). Castelli Graphics exhibitions from 1969-1996 and Castelli/Sonnabend Tapes and Films exhibitions from 1974-1984 are also included and are noted when known.
Note that this list is not comprehensive. In particular, Castelli Graphics exhibitions from the 1980s and early 1990s are incomplete. Sources used to compile this index include exhibition schedules and lists, installation photographs, announcements, clippings, and other printed materials from the Leo Castelli Gallery records, and the Leo Castelli Gallery website (www.castelligallery.com).
Exhibitions are listed in chronological order by title, if known, and gallery address.
1957 Season
Feb. First Exhibition: de Kooning, Delaunay, Dubuffet, Giacometti, Hartley, Leger, Mondrian, Picabia, Pollock, David Smith, van Doesburg; 4 E 77 St
Mar. 4-23, 1957 Jon Schueler; 4 E 77 St
Mar. 25 - Apr. 13, 1957 Viseux; 4 E 77 St
Apr. 15 - May 4, 1957 Paul Brach; 4 E 77 St
May 6-25, 1957 New Work: Bluhm, Budd, Dzubas, Johns, Leslie, Louis, Marisol, Ortman, Rauschenberg, Savelli; 4 E 77 St
1957-1958 Season
Oct. 1-26, 1957 Norman Bluhm; 4 E 77 St
Oct. 28 - Nov. 16, 1957 Horia Damian; 4 E 77 St
Nov. 18 - Dec. 14, 1957 Marisol; 4 E 77 St
Dec. 17, 1957 - Jan. 18, 1958 Collector's Annual; 4 E 77 St
Jan. 20 - Feb. 8, 1958 Jasper Johns; 4 E 77 St
Feb. 10 - Mar. 1, 1958 Friedel Dzubas; 4 E 77 St
Mar. 4-29, 1958 Robert Rauschenberg; 4 E 77 St
Apr. 1-26, 1958 Giuseppe Capogrossi; 4 E 77 St
Apr. 29 - May 31, 1958 Pioneers 1910-1950: de Kooning, Delaunay, Domela, Dubuffet, Giacometti, Hartley, Kandinsky, Leger, Miro, Picabia, Pollock, Schwitters, Smith, van Doejburg; 4 E 77 St
1958-1959 Season
Sept. 30 - Oct. 25, 1958 Angelo Savelli; 4 E 77 St
Oct. 28 - Nov. 22, 1958 Group Exhibition: Bluhm, Brach, Dzubas, Johns, Marisol, Rauschenberg, Schueler; 4 E 77 St
Nov. 25 - Dec. 20, 1958 Esteban Vicente, Drawings; 4 E 77 St
Jan. 6-24, 1959 Nassos Daphnis; 4 E 77 St
Jan. 27 - Feb. 14, 1959 Salvatore Scarpitta, Extramurals; 4 E 77 St
Feb. 17 - Mar. 7, 1959 Al Newbill; 4 E 77 St
Mar. 10-28, 1959 Gabriel Kohn; 4 E 77 St
Mar. 31 - Apr. 18, 1959 Norman Bluhm, Jean Dubuffet, and Robert Rauschenberg; 4 E 77 St
Apr. 21 - May 9, 1959 Jon Schueler; 4 E 77 St
May 12-30, 1959 Group Exhibition: Brach, Dzubas, Johns, Sander, Twombly; 4 E 77 St
1959-1960 Season
Oct. 6-17, 1959 Opening Exhibition of the New Gallery: Bluhm, Brach, Daphnis, Johns, Kohn, Rauschenberg, Sander, Scarpitta, Stella, Twombly; 4 E 77 St
Oct. 20 - Nov. 7, 1959 Work in Three Dimensions: Chamberlain, Follet, Giles, Johns, Klein, Kohn, Marisol, Nevelson, Ortman, Rauschenberg, Scarpitta; 4 E 77 St
Nov. 10-28, 1959 Ludwig Sander; 4 E 77 St
Dec. 1-26, 1959 Paul Brach; 4 E 77 St
Jan. 5-23, 1960 William Giles; 4 E 77 St
Jan. 26 - Feb. 13, 1960 Norman Bluhm; 4 E 77 St
Feb. 15 - Mar. 5, 1960 Jasper Johns; 4 E 77 St
Mar. 8-26, 1960 Nassos Daphnis; 4 E 77 St
Mar. 29 - Apr. 16, 1960 Robert Rauschenberg; 4 E 77 St
Apr. 19 - May 7, 1960 Salvatore Scarpitta; 4 E 77 St
May 10-28, 1960 Edward Higgins; 4 E 77 St
May 31 - June 25, 1960 Summary 1959-1960: Bluhm, Bontecou, Daphnis, Higgins, Johns, Kohn, Langlais, Rauschenberg, Sander, Scarpitta, Stella, Twombly, Tworkov; 4 E 77 St
1960-1961 Season
Sept. 27 - Oct. 15, 1960 Frank Stella; 4 E 77 St
Oct. 18 - Nov. 5, 1960 Cy Twombly; 4 E 77 St
Nov. 9 - Dec. 3, 1960 Lee Bontecou; 4 E 77 St
Dec. 6, 1960 - Jan. 7, 1961 Robert Rauschenberg, 34 Illustrations for Dante's Inferno; 4 E 77 St
Jan. 10-28, 1961 Frederick Kiesler; 4 E 77 St
Jan. 31 - Feb. 25, 1961 Jasper Johns, Drawings and Sculpture; 4 E 77 St
Feb. 28 - Mar. 18, 1961 Jack Tworkov; 4 E 77 St
Mar. 21 - Apr. 8, 1961 Bernard Langlais; 4 E 77 St
Apr. 11-29, 1961 Yves Klein, Le Monochrome; 4 E 77 St
May 2-20, 1961 Ludwig Sander; 4 E 77 St
May 23 - June [10], 1961 Sculpture and Relief: Bontecou, Chamberlain, Higgins, Scarpitta; 4 E 77 St
1961-1962 Season
Sept. 22 - Oct. 14, 1961 An Exhibition in Progress: Bontecou, Chamberlain, Daphnis, Higgins, Johns, Langlais, Moskowitz, Rauschenberg, Scarpitta, Stella, Twombly, Tworkov; 4 E 77 St
Oct. 17 - Nov. 4, 1961 Nassos Daphnis; 4 E 77 St
Nov. 7 - Dec. 5, 1961 Robert Rauschenberg; 4 E 77 St
Dec. 8, 1961 - Jan. 10, 1962 Group Exhibition: Bontecou, Johns, Langlais, [Lichtenstein], Scarpitta, Tworkov; 4 E 77 St
Jan. 13 - Feb. 6, 1962 John Chamberlain; 4 E 77 St
Feb. 10 - Mar. 3, 1962 Roy Lichtenstein; 4 E 77 St
Mar. 10 - Apr. 5, 1962 Robert Moskowitz; 4 E 77 St
Apr. 7-21, 1962 Group Exhibition: Bontecou, Chamberlain, Daphnis, Higgins, Rauschenberg, Scarpitta, Stella; 4 E 77 St
Apr. 28 - May 19, 1962 Frank Stella; 4 E 77 St
May 26 - June 30, 1962 Drawings: Bontecou, Johns, Lichtenstein, Moskowitz, Rauschenberg, Stella, Tworkov; 4 E 77 St
1962-1963 Season
Sept. 22 - Oct. 13, 1962 Group Exhibition: Chamberlain, Higgins, Johns, Klapheck, Rauschenberg, Scarpitta, Stella, Tinguely, Tworkov; 4 E 77 St
Oct. 16 - Nov. 7, 1962 John Chamberlain and Frank Stella; 4 E 77 St
Nov. 10 - Dec. 6, 1962 Lee Bontecou; 4 E 77 St
Dec. 8, 1962 - Jan. 9, 1963 Gerald van de Wiele; 4 E 77 St
Jan. 12 - Feb. 7, 1963 Jasper Johns; 4 E 77 St
Feb. 9 - Mar. 7, 1963 Jack Tworkov; 4 E 77 St
Mar. 9-30, 1963 Nassos Daphnis; 4 E 77 St
Apr. 2-25, 1963 Group Exhibition: Chamberlain, Higgins, Kiesler, Lichtenstein, Moskowitz, Rauschenberg, Stella, Twombly; 4 E 77 St
Apr. 27 - May 16, 1963 Salvatore Scarpitta; 4 E 77 St
May 20 - June 30, 1963 Group Drawing Exhibition: Bontecou, Daphnis, Johns, Lichtenstein, Moskowitz, Rauschenberg, Stella, Tworkov, van de Wiele; 4 E 77 St
1963-1964 Season
Sept. 28 - Oct. 24, 1963 Roy Lichtenstein; 4 E 77 St
Oct. 26 - Nov. 21, 1963 Robert Rauschenberg; 4 E 77 St
Nov. 23, 1963 - Jan. 2, 1964 Edward Higgins; 4 E 77 St
Jan. 4 - Feb. 6, 1964 Frank Stella; 4 E 77 St
Feb. 8 - Mar. 12, 1964 Group Exhibition: Chamberlain, Johns, Lichtenstein, Rauschenberg, Stella; 4 E 77 St
Mar. 14 - Apr. 9, 1964 Cy Twombly; 4 E 77 St
Apr. 11-30, 1964 John Chamberlain; 4 E 77 St
May 2 - June 3, 1964 Introducing Artschwager, Christo, Hay, Watts; 4 E 77 St
June 6-30, 1964 Group Exhibition: Chamberlain, Lichtenstein, Rauschenberg, Scarpitta, Stella, Twombly, Tworkov; 4 E 77 St
1964-1965 Season
Sept. 26 - Oct. 22, 1964 Group Exhibition: Artschwager, Lichtenstein, Rosenquist, Stella, Warhol; 4 E 77 St
Oct. 24 - Nov. 19, 1964 Roy Lichtenstein, Landscapes; 4 E 77 St
Nov. 21 - Dec. 28, 1964 Andy Warhol, Flower Paintings; 4 E 77 St
Jan. 9-27, 1965 John Chamberlain, Paintings; 4 E 77 St
Jan. 30 - Feb. 24, 1965 Richard Artschwager; 4 E 77 St
Feb. 27 - Mar. 24, 1965 Nassos Daphnis; 4 E 77 St
Mar. 27 - Apr. 14, 1965 Salvatore Scarpitta, Racing Cars; 4 E 77 St
Apr. 17 - May 13, 1965 James Rosenquist, F-111; 4 E 77 St
May 15 - June 9, 1965 Robert Rauschenberg, Oracle; 4 E 77 St
1965-1966 Season
Oct. 2-21, 1965 Group Exhibition: [Chamberlain], Johns, Lichtenstein, Poons, Rauschenberg, Stella, [Warhol]; 4 E 77 St
Oct. 23 - Nov. 17, 1965 Robert Bart; 4 E 77 St
Nov. 20 - Dec. 11, 1965 Roy Lichtenstein, Brushstrokes and Ceramics; 4 E 77 St
Dec. 14, 1965 - Jan. 5, 1966 Benefit Drawing Exhibition for the Foundation for the Contemporary Performance Arts; 4 E 77 St
Dec. 14, 1965 - Jan. 5, 1966 Group Exhibition; 4 E 77 St
Jan. 8 - Feb. 2, 1966 Jasper Johns; 4 E 77 St
Feb. 5 - Mar. 2, 1966 Donald Judd; 4 E 77 St
Feb. 12 - Mar. 2, 1966 Cy Twombly, Drawings; 4 E 77 St
Mar. 5 - Apr. 2, 1966 Frank Stella; 4 E 77 St
Apr. 6-27, 1966 Andy Warhol, Wallpaper and Clouds; 4 E 77 St
Apr. 30 - May 25, 1966 James Rosenquist; 4 E 77 St
May 28 - June 13, 1966 Christo, Storefront; 4 E 77 St
June 14-30, 1966 Group Exhibition: Bontecou, Johns, Judd, Lichtenstein, Poons, Rauschenberg, Rosenquist, Stella, Warhol; 4 E 77 St
1966-1967 Season
Oct. 8 - Nov. 8, 1966 Lee Bontecou; 4 E 77 St
Nov. 12 - Dec. 3, 1966 Edward Higgins; 4 E 77 St
Dec. 6-10, 1966 Benefit Group Exhibition for Experiments in Art and Technology, Inc.; 4 E 77 St
Dec. 7, 1966 - Jan. 5, 1967 Stanley Landsman; 4 E 77 St
Dec. 14, 1966 - Jan. 5, 1967 Group Exhibition: Artschwager, Lichtenstein, Rosenquist, Warhol; 4 E 77 St
Jan. 7-31, 1967 Larry Poons; 4 E 77 St
Feb. 4-26, 1967 Tenth Anniversary Exhibition: Artschwager, Bontecou, Chamberlain, Daphnis, Higgins, Johns, Judd, Lichtenstein, Morris, Poons, Rauschenberg, Rosenquist, Scarpitta, Stella, Twombly, Warhol; 4 E 77 St
Mar. 4-28, 1967 Robert Morris; 4 E 77 St
Apr. 1967 New Work: Chamberlain, Lichtenstein, Stella; 4 E 77 St
May 1967 Robert Rauschenberg, Revolvers; 4 E 77 St
1967-1968 Season
Oct. 7-26, 1967 Cy Twombly; 4 E 77 St
Oct. 28 - Nov. 18, 1967 Roy Lichtenstein; 4 E 77 St
Nov. 25 - Dec. 23, 1967 Frank Stella; 4 E 77 St
Dec. 30, 1967 - Jan. 23, 1968 Richard Artschwager, Sculptures and Reliefs; 4 E 77 St
Jan. 27 - Feb. 17, 1968 Bruce Nauman; 4 E 77 St
Feb. 24 - Mar. 16, 1968 Jasper Johns; 4 E 77 St